Later,
待会啊
use this nail to pin the eel down.
拿这钉子把这黄鳝钉上
I'll handle the rest.
剩下的我来处理
This is...
这就是
your...
您的
s-signature dish?
拿 拿手菜
Yeah,
对啊
braised eel.
红烧鳝鱼啊
Let me tell you,
我跟你说啊
my wife and Wang Tian both love it.
你这阿姨和王天都喜欢吃这个
W-Wang Tian loves eel?
王 王天爱吃这个啊
You're not afraid of eels, are you?
你不会连鳝鱼都怕吧
I'm telling you,
我告诉你啊
Wang Tian hates cowardly men the most.
王天最讨厌胆小的男人
I-I'm not!
我 我没有啊
I never said I was afraid.
我可没说我害怕
I can do it.
我可以的
Hold it.
拿着啊
Remember, nail the head.
记着钉头啊
Be careful not to nail your hand.
小心别钉着手
Auntie!
阿姨
You're back!
你们回来了
Yu Bo, you came.
余波来了
Why are you covered in so much mud?
这个身上怎么那么多泥巴呀
My mom insisted on checking out the construction site.
我妈非要去工地
You're a civil engineering professor,
你说你一个土木系教授
not a contractor.
又不是包工头
Look at the mess on your clothes.
看这身上弄的
A student of mine wanted me to take a look at their project.
自己学生的项目让我去看一眼
Of course, I had to go, right?
我肯定得去对吧
Yeah.
是
Wang Tian, let me tell you...
王天我跟你说
Well...
那
What's wrong?
怎么了
Why are you gagging?
你干嘛
Am I making you sick?
看到我要吐啊
No, I...
不是 我
It's just a reflex.
本能反应
Excuse me.
你等一下
You guys clean up first.
你们先收拾
I n-need to go to the bathroom.
我去 去趟厕所
Is he okay?
没事吧
Mom,
妈
are you okay?
你没事吧
-Hello, Professor Kang. -And this is?
康老师好 这位是
This is Ms. Lin Wanxing,
这位是林晚星老师
a fellow teacher
你的同行
and my girlfriend.
我的女朋友
Hello, Ms. Lin.
林老师好 林老师好
Nice to meet you.
您好
Kang Qiao.
康桥
You're back.
你回来了
W-What happened?
这 这怎么了
Nothing. I'm just happy to be home.
没有啊 很开心回家
Ms. Lin,
林老师
I-I'll go wash up.
我 我 我洗一洗啊
I'm a mess.
这乱七八糟
You guys keep her company.
你们招待一下啊
You invited Ms. Lin over
你把小林老师叫来
without telling Mom beforehand?
居然不提前跟妈讲
And Ms. Lin just happened to catch Mom looking so disheveled.
还正好碰上她这么狼狈的样子
Wang,
老王
you're dead.
你完了
Wait.
不是
I made eel.
鳝鱼
And braised!
红烧的
Let's all raise a glass to welcome
咱们举杯欢迎一下
Ms. Lin Wanxing.
小林老师
Thank you.
谢谢
Welcome, welcome.
欢迎 欢迎 欢迎
Oh, right.
对了
This is your favorite,
这是你最爱吃的
braised eel.
红烧黄鳝
If you don't like it,
你不喜欢吃
let's switch to another dish.
咱们换一个菜
Let's switch to another dish.
换一个
This is the one you love.
这个是你爱吃的
Thank you.
谢谢
This one...
这个
Let me do it. Let me.
我来 我来 我来
How about this?
要不这样吧
Well,
那个
tomorrow I'll come back and make you
明天我回来再给你做一个
braised soft-shell turtle—
红烧甲鱼
freshly slaughtered.
现杀的
Yu.
小余
Yu can do it.
小余行
He has great knife skills.
他刀工可好了
No, no, r-really, I can't.
不不不 我不 不必
My knife skills aren't good.
我刀工不好
Not good at all.
不好
This is Wanxing's first time visiting our home.
这小林老师第一次来家里做客
Why didn't you tell me beforehand?
怎么也不跟我说一声啊
Why keep it from me?
干嘛瞒着我呀
Well...
这
It's just that
不是
you've been so busy lately with research,
你最近这是搞研究忙
writing papers,
又是写论文吧
and running around to construction sites.
又是跑工地
I didn't want you to wear yourself out.
怕你太累了
So,
所以这
whatever I could handle myself,
我能干的事
I just went ahead a-and did it.
我就自己就就就干了
This whole table of dishes—
这么一大桌菜
it must have taken you all afternoon.
弄了一下午吧
Just about 4 or 5 hours.
也就四五个小时
It was fine.
还行
Mom,
妈
for all the hard work Dad put into this meal,
你看在我爸做饭有功
forgive him this time.
饶了他这一次吧
Dad,
爸
punish yourself with a drink,
你自罚一杯
and this matter will be over.
这事就翻篇了
That's my boy.
你是我亲儿子
Your Majesty,
老婆大人
I was wrong.
错了错了
Blessings to the Empress Dowager.
太后吉祥
At ease.
免礼
Wanxing,
小林
try this dish.
试试这个菜
It's my husband's specialty.
是我们家老王的拿手好菜
Give it a try.
试一试
This is my signature dish, braised eel.
这是我最拿手的红烧鳝鱼
It's a secret recipe.
独家秘方
You can't get it anywhere else.
你在外头吃不着
Come on, try it.
你尝尝 尝尝 尝尝
My wife and Tian both love it the most.
她们母女俩最爱这口
Ms. Lin, I want some.
小林老师 我想吃
You just can't help yourself, can you?
怎么哪都有你的事啊
These noodles look great.
这面看着不错呀
Let me try the broth first.
我先尝口这汤
The broth is what makes the noodles, right?
面就得看汤是不是
This is also Chairman Wang's specialty.
这也是董事长拿手好菜
Dad,
爸
the broth is made from eel bones, right?
这个汤底是黄鳝骨熬的对吧
Right.
对
You just love the flavor, right?
你不就喜欢喝这个吗
Uncle and Auntie,
那个叔叔阿姨
let me propose a toast.
我敬您俩一杯那个
I need to use the restroom.
我要去趟厕所
What a lightweight.
这什么酒量啊
Wanxing,
小林老师
a toast to you.
我敬你
What are you doing?
你干嘛呢
Making her drink on her first visit?
第一次上门就让人喝酒啊
I'll finish mine, and you do as you like.
我干了你随意
-Okay? -You're putting her on the spot.
好吧 那人喝不喝
If she doesn't drink, it's disrespectful to you, right?
不喝不尊重你对吧
That's not it.
那不是
In this house,
在咱们家啊
whether you respect me or not doesn't matter.
尊不尊重我无所谓
But you must respect the lady of the house,
必须得尊重女主人
right?
是吧
Blessings to the Empress Dowager.
太后吉祥
Come on, come on.
来 来 来
Right,
对了
Wanxing,
林老师
do you know
你知道我为什么
why I felt an instant connection with you?
跟你就一见如故吗
That's because
因为啊
you're very much like our Professor Kang.
你特别像我们家康老师
I didn't study hard when I was a kid,
我是小的时候没好好读书
so I'm not very educated.
没什么文化
One year, when I was doing business in Shenzhen,
有一年在这深圳做生意的时候
I had a client whose surname was Situ.
我 人有一个老板姓司徒
I even
我还
tried to act clever and asked him,
自作聪明 我还问人家
"Sir,
我说先生
is it that your father's surname is Si
请问是不是你的父亲姓司
and your mother's surname is Tu?"
你的母亲姓徒啊
That was so embarrassing.
这 这脸丢大了
Things like that happened a lot.
这种事好多
So
所以啊
I've always believed
我始终认为
that every family
这家里头
needs an intelligent, well-educated woman—
必须得有一个有才识的女人
that's what makes a household prosper.
她才能旺家
Remember that.
记住了
Back then, I basically wore Professor Kang down with my persistence
当时我就完全靠着死缠烂打
until she agreed to be with me.
这才追上我们康老师
I heard you were once the top scorer on the college entrance exam, right?
听说你是高考状元是吧
What was your score?
你多少分啊
Seven hundred and six points.
七百零六分
See? See?
你看看 你看看
Compared to our Professor Kang,
这个跟我们家康老师比
you're no couch.
那也是不穷多让
"No slouch."
不遑多让
Right, it's "no slouch." No slouch.
不遑 不遑 不遑多让 不遑
Anyway,
总之
thank you so much
非常感谢你
for choosing our Wang Fa.
能看上我们家王法
To be honest, I also think
我说实话我也觉得
you two are a perfect match.
王法跟你特别般配
He's not like
他不像外头
those delusional guys out there who are
有些那种癞蛤蟆啊
always chasing someone way out of their league.
他总想吃天鹅肉
Right, daughter?
是吧闺女
Dad.
爸
Come on, eat up.
吃菜吃菜吃菜
Let's have a drink together.
咱们一起喝一杯吧
Come on, come on.
来来来
Cheers, cheers.
喝一个喝一个
Cheers.
来
Welcome, Wanxing.
欢迎小林老师
Welcome, welcome.
欢迎欢迎欢迎
Don't drink too much.
你少喝一点
I'm just happy.
开心嘛
Just a little bit.
一点点
Just a little.
一点点而已
Then eat more.
那多吃点
That's amazing.
太牛了
Don't let me have all the fun.
别光我玩啊
You young people,
年轻人啊
be more lively.
活跃一点
Don't just sit there with your phones.
别光看手机了
Come here. Come on.
过来过来过来
-Okay, I'll play. -Go.
好 来来来 快去
Let me play with you.
我来 我来
Why do you have to be part of everything?
怎么哪都有你啊
I'm actually pretty good at this.
我玩得很好的
Really.
真的
Is that so?
是吗
I may be getting on in years,
我这个年纪虽然有点大
but I still have a strong competitive streak.
但我胜负心还是比较强的
See? I knew you were no good.
我就说你不行嘛
And you just had to...
你真是这
Wanxing,
小林
Wang Fa, come here.
王法你们过来
Wanxing, if you don't know how,
小林你不会
let Wang Fa teach you.
让王法教你
Come on, come on.
来来来
She has zero athletic talent.
小林老师运动天赋为零
I'll do it.
我来
Let me play some rounds with our chairman.
我来陪我们董事长玩
Let Wanxing play.
你让小林来呀
-Dad is on a completely different level. -Let me get familiar with it first.
董事长是在降维打击
He used to spear fish on the production team back in the day.
他以前在生产队叉鱼的
Come here and let the kids play.
你过来让给孩子玩
Well, some things are better left unsaid.
这看破不说破
Let me give it a try.
我来试试吧
How about
怎么样
we have a round?
比一局
Sure.
比
Okay.
好
I think that's fine.
我觉得没问题
He sucks at darts.
他飞镖很菜的
Anyway, if you lose,
反正你输了
you have to do whatever she says.
你要听她的
I'll give you a head start.
让你一局
You go first.
你先来
This is going to be good.
有戏看了
Challenge accepted.
接受挑战
-Clearly didn't inherit my genes. -You really suck,
一看就没遗传到我叉鱼的基因
little brother.
老弟
Step aside.
让位吧
Come on, Wanxing!
小林老师加油啊
Not bad.
可以啊
See? I knew Wanxing was good.
我就说小林老师可以的嘛
Okay, you lost.
好你输了
What do you want him to do?
你想让他做什么
I have a suggestion.
我有个建议
Have you seen the photos of him in women's clothes?
你看过他穿女装的照片吗
The one
就是
where he's wearing a qipao with a flower crown?
旗袍簪花那个
I just saw the photo upstairs.
刚在楼上看过
Isn't that hilarious?
是不是很好笑
Okay.
好了
How about a qipao and flower crown?
你穿旗袍簪花怎么样
Are you asking for it?
你找死是不是啊
I think that's a great idea.
我觉得这个提议不错
Duly noted.
记下了
That's so fun, honey.
来 挺好 老婆
Come on, come on,
来来来
honey,
老婆
how about I take you along to try the flower crown too?
要不要我也带你一起去簪花啊
Come on, we're already here.
不是来都来了嘛
Just play one round.
就来一局嘛
No.
不玩
I'm very busy.
我很忙的
We have a guest,
客人在
and you're just sitting here glued to your phone.
你也就是看手机看手机看手机
Fine.
好啊
If I win,
那我要是赢了
you're not allowed to hang around my office for no reason anymore.
你以后不许没事往我办公室晃荡
And if I win,
那要是我赢了
you have to agree to one request of mine.
你要答应我一个要求
Deal.
没问题
Give the darts to them.
给他们玩
You got this.
加油
Yu Bo used to compete in
余波之前在英国
professional dart tournaments back in the UK.
打过专业飞镖比赛
No wonder he's so confident.
难怪他这么胸有成竹的
Nice!
好
As expected of Kang Qiao's daughter.
不愧是康桥的女儿
So amazing.
就是厉害
Wait.
不是
Seriously?
不是吧
When Wanxing hit the board,
刚刚小林老师中的时候
you applauded so enthusiastically.
掌声那么热烈
How come it's so cold when it's my turn?
怎么到我这边就变得这么冷淡
Alright, go ahead.
好了你说吧
What's your request?
你什么要求
My request is that...
我的要求是
you really look at me.
你能好好地看我
Look me in the eye, properly.
正眼好好地看我
I just did.
看过了
You're even more ordinary than this quarter's financial report.
比公司这季度的报表还要普通
My sister's a master roaster.
我姐嘴就是毒
How am I a master roaster?
我怎么就嘴毒了
Your words are savage,
你不光嘴毒
and your actions are even worse.
你还行为恶劣
-Let's all play. Let me show you. -You started that flower crown thing.
一起玩一起玩
I still haven't settled that score with you.
我还没跟你算簪花那个账呢
You were smiling so happily in that photo
你看你小时候那张照片
from when you were a kid.
笑得多开心啊
I'll stick this dart in you.
飞镖扎你
D-Don't...
别别
Dad,
爸
look at him.
你看他
Let Dad show you how it's done.
老爸给你们做个示范啊
You can't lose to someone like him.
这种人你能输他吗
Watch carefully.
你看着点啊
It's too rowdy in here.
这里啊太闹腾了
Want to go out for some fresh air?
咱们出去透透气
Standard posture.
标准姿势啊
Watch carefully.
你看着点
-Dad, you're so good. -Well, the old fox still has his tricks.
不愧是老王
Please excuse
让你见笑了
our family.
我们这一家子
My husband can be a bit much sometimes,
王根发有时候跟小孩一样
like a big kid.
容易招人烦
No.
没有
He's very nice.
叔叔人很好
You're all wonderful.
你们都很好
I think you're wonderful too.
我觉得你也很好啊
The moment I saw you today, I thought,
我今天一看到你我就想
"I wish we'd met sooner."
我怎么不早点认识你呢
Have you...
您
heard about my past?
听说过我之前的事吗
Does that matter?
很重要吗
I like looking at the stars.
我也喜欢看星星
Take the Andromeda Galaxy
就拿现在我们看到
we're looking at now, for example.
这个仙女座来说吧
It's about
它距离我们有
2.54 million light-years away.
二百五十四万光年
It's about twice the size of the Milky Way,
比银河系还大 大约一倍
with over a trillion stars.
拥有上万亿颗的恒星
Yet to us,
可在人类眼里
it's nothing more
它就是一个
than a blurry patch of light.
模糊的一个光斑
Its vastness,
它的庞大
its profundity,
它的悠远
its brilliance,
它的璀璨
its true form—
它真实的样子
most people
其实
never truly
大多数人类
understand any of it.
都不是很了解的
But so what?
这又能怎么样呢
Humanity's limited perspective and incomplete understanding
人类片面的视角和有限的观察
don't change
也不能影响它
its objective existence
客观的存在
or its timeless beauty.
和它永恒的美丽啊
I understand now.
我明白了
Actually, since my husband
其实我们家王根发
likes you so much,
这么喜欢你啊
he must have looked into your past.
他肯定调查过你了
He's not as clueless as he seems.
他这人没看起来那么傻
Of course, he's not exactly smart either.
当然也没那么聪明啊
He went bankrupt twice.
破产过两次
Good thing my income is stable.
还好我收入比较稳定
Otherwise, our whole family would be out on the street.
不然我们全家要喝西北风去了
Actually...
其实
ever since
王法
Wang Fa's student
自从他的学生
had that accident,
出了事以后
he's been carrying it with him.
他一直很消沉
We tried everything we could
我们全家想了各种各样的方法
to make him
想让他
happy again.
开心起来
But nothing really worked.
都挺难的
Today,
我今天
seeing him laugh...
看他笑得
laugh that wholeheartedly...
笑得那么开心
made me so, so happy.
真的好高兴好高兴
I think
我想
you're the one who brought him out of it.
是你把他带出来的
For your sake, he's
他为你
finally opened his heart again.
敞开了自己
Thank you.
谢谢你
Son.
儿子
Do you have to go back to Hongjing?
你非得回宏景吗
The guest rooms are all empty.
那家里的客房都还空着呢
I can stay!
我可以住
Which room will I be staying in?
我住哪一间
Are you...
是不是你小
I'm talking to my son.
跟我儿子说话呢
Why are you moving around so much?
你动手动脚干什么呀
No,
不是
Uncle, listen to me!
叔叔你听我说
I'm only 3 months and 4 days older than Wang Tian.
我就比王天大三个月零四天
Tian, tell him
小天你说是不是
I'm only that much older than you.
我就比你大那么多
Okay. Yes, yes.
好好 是是是
Quick, have the driver take this drunk home.
快让司机把这醉鬼送回去
No! I...
我不要我
I want Fa to take me back.
我要小法送我
-Okay, I'll take you. -What a lightweight.
好 这小酒量 我送我送
You're my former manager after all.
好歹是前经纪人嘛
Uncle, Auntie, thank you for today.
叔叔阿姨今天麻烦了
Come by often from now on.
以后常来啊
Come by often.
常来
We're really glad you came.
特别好
We're leaving.
走了
Drive safely on the road.
注意安全啊
We will.
我们会的
Such a lightweight.
这小酒量
So weak.
真菜
What are you smiling about?
笑什么
I just think
我就是觉得
your family is really lovable.
你的家人都很可爱
I'm so jealous.
真羡慕
From now on...
以后
they'll be your family too.
他们也都是你的家人
Is this how you treat your comrade-in-arms?
你就这么对你的革命战友啊
Who said I'm his comrade-in-arms?
谁跟他是革命战友啊
Then,
那
what are we going to do with him tonight?
他今晚怎么处理
Let him stay at your place?
住你家
Okay.
好啊
That obedient?
这么听话
My family tradition:
我家的传统
the lady of the house makes the decisions.
那就是女主人说了算
Just kiss her if you want to.
想亲就亲啊
Why are you dragging it out?
磨磨蹭蹭干什么
Let's go home.
回家
Do you know
你知道
he was trying to sneak a kiss from you just now?
刚刚他想要偷偷亲亲你吗
Ms. Lin.
小林老师
Tell me honestly.
你要实话跟我说
Am I really that ordinary?
我是不是很普通啊
Not at all.
没有啊
I think you're very special.
我觉得你很特别啊
Right? Aren't I?
对不对 是不是
Aren't I?
是不是啊
Let me tell you,
我跟你说啊
my handsomeness has layers.
我的帅是超级有层次的那种
But Tian just can't appreciate it.
可是小天她看不出来
I'm warning you,
我警告你啊
if you can't keep your hands to yourself,
你下手再这么没轻没重
I'll dump you by the roadside to feed the dogs.
我丢你在路边喂狗
Doggie.
狗狗
Where's the doggie?
狗狗在哪里
The doggie's over there.
狗狗在那里
You were trying to sneak a kiss from me just now?
刚刚想要偷亲我呀
If I were a doggie,
如果我是狗狗的话
I'd want to be a Cavalier King Charles Spaniel.
我要做查理王
You'd better not be a dog.
你最好不要是狗
Cavalier King Charles Spaniels are so cute.
查理王多可爱
Wrong way.
走错了
Rest early. Good night.
早点休息 晚安
Good night.
晚安
Thank you for today.
你辛苦了
Thank you for everything today too.
也辛苦你哦
I could also be a Golden Retriever.
我也可以做大金毛
Hello?
喂
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
Wang Fa lost to you!
王法输给你
When are you making him wear a flower crown?
什么时候让他去簪花呀
Can you just sleep quietly, you drunkard?
你这酒鬼能不能老实睡
Hello.
喂
Don't listen to him.
你别理他啊
Okay.
好
Noted.
我记得了
Okay to what?
好什么
To take you to try on a flower crown tomorrow.
明天去簪花啊
A bet's a bet, Mr. Win.
愿赌服输哦 赢先生
Fine.
好
Rest early.
你早点休息
You too.
你也是
Ivory,
小白
a bet's a bet.
愿赌服输
What do you think of me in this outfit?
你觉得我穿这一身
Fix your hair.
头发弄一下
-It looks good. -It really suits you.
挺好看的 挺合适的
Excuse me.
让一下
Come, stand a little further forward.
来往前站一点
Look here.
来看这边
Sorry.
不好意思啊
I think I'm a bit too rough-looking
我觉得我弄簪花
and too tan for the flower crown look.
我太糙了点 太黑了点
Relax.
你放心
Places like this usually do pretty heavy makeup.
这种店妆都化得很浓的
They'll make you nice and fair.
包白
Let's go.
走
Okay, one more.
好 再来一张
Look.
你看啊
[No More Anxiety]
这一套你喜欢吗
So pretty.
好好看
So beautiful.
好漂亮啊
Here, and there's more in the back too.
这 还有后面还有
I like this one as well.
我觉得这个也不错
Yeah.
是啊
We should take photos in a few more outfits.
咱俩得多拍几套
Okay. Do you have sample pictures?
行 您这有样图吗
Could you recommend a few?
这个您推荐一下
Yes, yes.
有有有
This one's lovely.
好看嘞
Come on.
来
Does this look good on me?
好看吗
Yes.
好看
Let me take a picture of you.
我给你拍照片
Alright.
好了
Okay.
该你了
Hey, you two,
美女帅哥
would you like flower crowns?
要簪花吗
Ma'am, my boyfriend wants it.
阿姨我男朋友想要簪花
Sure.
可以啊
My hair's too short to pin anything into, right?
我头发这么短簪不了吧
Even bald people can wear flower crowns.
秃头都可以簪
Hear that?
听到没
A bet is a bet.
愿赌服输
I'll go pick a color for you.
我去帮你挑个颜色
Yellow, maybe.
黄色的吧
It's more elegant.
淡雅一点
It was clearly a pink one in the photo,
照片里明明是粉色
bright pink.
艳粉
It suits you perfectly.
太适配了
Let me think—
让我想想
we're still missing a women's qipao.
好像还差一件女式旗袍
Well,
不
do we really have to recreate it exactly?
倒也没必要这么还原吧
Ms. Lin,
小林老师
please,
求求啊
let me off this time.
放过我吧
Alright then.
那好吧
But since we're here,
但是来都来了
I'll wear a flower crown myself.
我来簪
I think
我看
it's you who wanted to wear one
小林老师从一开始
from the very beginning.
就想自己簪吧
That's right.
没错
The moment I saw your photo,
在看见你照片的那一刻起
my heart was already set on it.
我就已经心动了
Ma'am, could you pick a color for me?
阿姨你给我挑个颜色
Alright.
我给你挑哦
After you're done, you can go take pictures by the seaside.
簪完了可以去海边拍拍照
It'll look so pretty.
好好看
The seaside?
海边
Yeah.
对啊
The beach around here is quite beautiful.
我们这边海边还挺漂亮的
Photos look even better there.
海边拍照更美
Look.
你看
There's a message in a bottle over there.
那有个漂流瓶
What a coincidence.
好巧
It really is... quite a coincidence.
还真是 好巧呢
Why don't you open it?
要不打开看看
Don't tell me
你该不会是说
there's an engagement ring hidden inside.
里面藏着一枚求婚戒指吧
No ring.
没有戒指
It's an application form.
是一张申请表
When I accompanied you back to Yongchuan University last time,
上次陪你回永川大学的时候
Director Jia asked
贾主任问你
if you wanted to go back and finish your PhD.
之后还想不想继续读博
From the look in your eyes at that time,
我看你的眼神
♪ With every part of you ♪
应该是想的
♪ Our words flow ♪
我肯定没有看错
So this whole elaborate plan...
你这么大费周章
was all for this?
就是为了这个
After we finish the last match,
等带完最后一场比赛
the kids will have to prepare for the college entrance exam.
孩子们就得准备高考了
I think after that,
我觉得在那之后
you should start a new chapter too.
你也得开始新生活了
When did you prepare this?
什么时候准备的
Early this morning.
一大早
I forced Yu Bo to come and do it.
逼余波过来的
I couldn't let him put me through all that last night for nothing.
不能让他白折腾我一晚上
More than being my wife,
比起做王法的老婆
I want you...
我更希望
to be the radiant, shining Lin Wanxing you are.
你是闪闪发光的林晩星
Are you still going to take photos of me?
你还给我拍照吗
I'll do it right now.
现在就拍
What should we eat later?
一会吃点啥
Boss,
老大
Wen Chengye.
文成业
-Wen! -Wen Chengye!
小文 文成业
don't forget the team meeting this afternoon.
别忘了球队下午开会啊
-Got it. -It's about us reaching the finals!
知道了 说咱们踢进决赛的事
Did you hear that?
听见没有
We made it to the finals!
踢进决赛
Got it!
知道了
Qin Ao is so handsome.
秦敖好帅啊
They made it to the finals.
进总决赛了
Qin Ao is so cool!
秦敖 好帅喔
Qin Ao, you're so cool!
好帅啊 秦敖
Let's go watch it together!
我们一起去看吧
So cool!
好帅呀
Go for it!
加油
Look what this is.
都看看
Everyone!
同学们
Hello, Director.
主任好
-Take a look at these. -Hello, Director.
看看这是什么 主任好
I heard from Ms. Lin
听林老师说
that you guys like this place's milk tea the best.
你们最喜欢喝这家奶茶了
Today, I, Qian,
今天我老钱
paid out of my own pocket
自掏腰包
to reward all our warriors!
慰劳众将士
Good job, everyone!
大家辛苦
Thank you, Director!
谢谢主任 来一口 哪个
Director,
主任
you're being awfully generous today.
你今天大放血啊
Was I really that stingy before?
难道我以前很抠吗
Of course.
肯定抠啊
Isn't this the first time you've ever bought us anything?
这不第一次给我们买吗
Alright.
好
I'll buy more next time!
下次我多买
Students...
同学们
Director Qian,
老师
you might as well just call us "little brats" like before.
你还是叫我们兔崽子吧
It's more affectionate.
亲切
Alright,
好
little brats!
小兔崽子们
I'm really happy today.
今天确实很高兴啊
Seeing how far you've all come
你们大家能有今天
makes every bit of it worthwhile—
也不枉我老钱
all those hours I spent
戴着老花镜
wearing my reading glasses, helping you fill your composition grids
一格一格地给你们爬着田字格
one square at a time, and copying English poems line by line.
一行一行地给你们抄着英文诗啊
It was all worth it.
值了
Alright.
好
I'm here today
今天我来到这里
representing the school
是代表学校
to talk to you all about
来给大家讲一讲
the special admission policy.
单招这个政策
I think they had it last year.
去年好像有
Special admission.
单招
What exactly is it?
什么是单招呢
Well, the football game
不是马上
is about to start,
就要开始足球比赛
and it's the finals.
而且是决赛
If you win
如果在这次决赛中
the championship,
你们能获得冠军
3 players among you
你们中间的三位球员
may qualify for special university admission.
就可能获得单招进入大学的资格
That's what special admission means.
这就是单招
Director,
主任
how many points can it lower the admission threshold by?
单招的话能降多少分录取啊
I looked into it.
我查了
Based on your current grades,
根据你们现在的成绩啊
if you guys push a little harder,
如果大家再努上一把力
you should be able to reach
是能够够得着
the score requirement for special admission.
单招这个分数线的
Does it only apply if we win the championship?
必须是冠军才可以吗
Well, of course, the runner-up works too.
那当然亚军也可以啊
It's just that there won't be
只是没有这个
those 3
三个单招
fixed special admission slots.
这个固定的名额了
So obviously, winning the championship is better.
那当然还是获得冠军好嘛
Really,
真的
the school hopes you can achieve good results.
学校是希望你们能获得好成绩
[Special Admission]
但是
I'd
我老钱啊
also like to say
也有些心里话
a few words from the heart.
想跟大家絮叨絮叨
I still remember two years ago,
记得两年前啊
when you first came to this school.
我是看着你们进到这个学校里的
You were even rowdier back then.
你们当时比现在还闹腾
But
但是
your eyes were shining with light.
两个眼睛里都有光
I thought to myself then
我当时就觉得
that you were a bunch of good boys with ambition.
你们是一群有抱负的好小伙子
But not long after,
可是没过多久啊
your class fell apart,
班级散了
and so did your spirits.
人心也散了
Especially
特别是
that light in your eyes—
眼睛那两道光
I could no longer see it.
我老是看不见了
It worried me deeply.
我心里着急啊
I really wanted to do something for you,
我真想为你们做些什么
but
可是
there was only so much I could do.
心有余而力不足啊
Later,
后来呢
Mr. Lin found me
林爷爷找到了我
and asked me to be this "mystery person"
让我做这个神秘人
to carry out this secret plan.
来执行这个神秘计划
I was very happy.
我很高兴啊
I agreed on the spot
我毫不犹豫
without a moment's hesitation.
我当场就答应了
I have always believed
我始终认为啊
that as an educator,
作为一名教育工作者
we must never let
一定不能让学生
the fire in the students' hearts go out.
心里那把火熄灭了
And now, I'm truly happy
我现在很高兴啊
to see
看到大家
that fire burning bright in your hearts once again.
心里那把火又重新燃烧起来
Really.
真的
No matter whether you win
不管这次你们这个冠军
the championship this time or not,
能不能得到
in my heart,
在我的心里
you are all the best.
你们都是这个
I can proudly say
我可以自豪地说
that I
我
am a teacher of Hongjing No. 8 High School's star football team.
是宏景八中明星足球队的老师
Our football players
我们这帮足球队员
are the best.
是最棒的
The absolute best.
最棒的
Qian,
老钱头
the other day, Chen Jianghe and I snuck off with your bike
那天我跟陈江河偷玩你车
and ended up breaking it.
给你车玩坏了
Now it makes a rattling noise whenever you ride it.
现在你骑着都嘎嘎响
Don't worry.
你放心
I'll definitely fix it for you.
我一定给它修好
Good.
好
Since you're being real with me,
你们够意思
I've got to be real with you too.
我也得再够意思一把
I wasn't going to tell you at first,
本来不想跟你们说
but now
现在
I'll share another piece of good news with you.
我再告诉大家一个好消息
In order to
学校呢
let you focus wholeheartedly on preparing for the finals,
为了安心让你们备战这次决赛
starting next week,
从下个礼拜起
the school is giving you 2 weeks off
给你们放假两周
for intensive training!
集训训练
Two weeks?
两周
Thank you, Director!
谢谢主任
Alright, alright!
好了好了好了
M-M-My job here is done.
我 我 我的任务完成了啊
You guys, enjoy the milk tea.
你们喝奶茶
-Enjoy the milk tea. -Okay, okay.
喝奶茶啊 好的好的
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
拜拜 拜拜 拜拜
See you tomorrow!
明天见
That's great!
太好了
Fight on, guys!
加油兄弟们
-Fight on! -Yeah!
加油 加油
Just got the news—
刚刚得到消息
Hengjiu defeated their opponent 7-0 with ease
恒久七比零轻松战胜对手
and advanced to the Youth Super League finals.
杀进青超决赛
We fought tooth and nail to advance,
咱们踢得鼻青脸肿的
while they cruised through.
人家轻轻松松
That final boss really is a final boss,
这大魔王就是大魔王
scoring like that in the semifinals.
半决赛就能拿这个分
They're just
这实力简直跟我们
in a league of their own.
不是一个次元啊
When we face them in the finals,
到时候踢决赛的时候
it'll be like two bitter rivals
就是仇人相见
going head-to-head.
分外眼红
Starting tomorrow,
明天开始
we'll focus on analyzing Hengjiu's playing style and discuss
集中分析恒久的风格
-targeted tactics for the finals. -Coach has new strategies.
讨论决赛的针对性战术打法
But
可是
no matter how good the tactics are,
这战术再厉害
can we really beat the final boss?
是不是也赢不了大魔王啊
After all, in our last match against them,
毕竟我们上一次比赛
they scored 11 goals against us.
他们灌了我们十一个球
You can still eat?
你还吃得下
Why wouldn't I?
我为什么吃不下
Is being this dejected
你们这么垂头丧气
going to help you win the match?
踢比赛的时候就能赢了
Well said.
说得对
Eat as much as we can now,
现在使劲吃
and give it everything we've got on the field later.
到时候使劲踢
Not eating?
不吃
I'm eating then.
我吃了
Come on, eat up.
吃吧吃吧吃吧
I think we should stop being intimidated.
我觉得大家也别有畏难情绪
Who cares if they're the final boss?
管他是大魔王呢
At least we have a chance to compete against them.
至少我们有同台竞争的机会
Cheer up, guys.
打起精神来吧
Just do our best.
加油就完了
-Come on, guys. -Yeah.
加油加油 对呀
Cheer up, guys.
打起精神来
That's right.
对呀
And we've got a world-class coach.
咱们还有国际水准大教练呢
We have to master the 4-4-2 Formation.
我们一定要把四四二给练好
That way, we won't panic and let Yongchuan Hengjiu
这样在面对永川恒久的时候
throw us off our game.
才不会自乱阵脚
So where are we going to train?
那我们去哪里训练
Where else?
还能去哪
The school field.
学校操场呗
We only have two weeks left.
我们只有两周的时间了
And they have PE classes there every day.
并且他们每天都会上体育课
Realistically, we only have
实际上留给我们的时间
about half a day to train.
也就半天左右
Besides, the school closes every day,
而且学校每天都会关门
so we won't even be able to use the field.
训练场地也就用不了了
And now with new tactics too,
现在又有了新的战术
there's simply no time to get everything in sync.
根本没有时间磨合
That makes sense.
有道理
Then, where does Yongchuan Hengjiu
那永川恒久他们
usually train?
平时在哪训练
This is their training field.
这是他们的训练场地
-Oh my god. -What the hell?
我的天
I've never trained at a place
我还没在这么高规模的地方
this high-end before.
训练过呢
So what if their field's so fancy?
场地再好有啥用
Doesn't mean a thing if you can't win,
踢不赢说啥都白给
right?
对不
Don't chicken out.
咱别㏺啊
Just go for it.
就是上
Yeah.
对
When have I ever been afraid of anyone?
我怕过谁啊 对吧
-You can't defeat me. -Let me take another look.
踢不过我 你让我再看一眼
Let me see.
让我再看
Get your spirits up, will you?
有点士气 行不行
Wait.
不是
Are you serious?
认真的吗
As for aerobic endurance,
有氧耐力的话
I think our midfielders are the ones who need to focus on it.
我觉得就我们中场练比较合适
Zheng Ren, what do you think?
郑仁你有什么想法
Actually, I think aerobic endurance
其实有氧耐力的话
helps with
其实这是非常适合
those short bursts
因为在我们
of explosive movement, you know?
短期内爆发的东西吧
And Fu, I think you should train more on that too.
然后老付我觉得你也可以多练练
Yeah, we need to work on it together.
是 我们要一起
No.
不是
My former manager,
前经纪人
do me a favor.
帮我个忙呗
Zheng Ren!
郑仁
Pass the ball!
传球
Over here!
来一下
Chen Jianghe!
陈江河
It's okay, it's okay.
没事没事没事
Keep moving forward, forward.
往前走
Zheng Ren!
郑仁
You've watched this match footage over a dozen times already.
这场比赛你都看了十几遍了
Yeah.
是啊
The more I watch it, the more anxious I get.
越看越焦虑
What should we do?
那怎么办啊
We don't even have a proper training facility
我们也没有专业场地
for specialized drills.
做针对性训练
Are we definitely going to lose?
是不是输定了
Don't worry.
你放心吧
I'm their coach.
我是他们的教练
This is my job.
这是我的工作
I'm confiscating
焦虑源
your source of anxiety.
没收
All set.
搞定
Come on.
走
Let's go out for a drink.
我们出去喝一杯
A drink?
喝一杯
If you want to drink, why don't we just make something at your place?
要喝酒的话去你家调不就好了
The atmosphere is different.
那氛围不一样
Going out for a walk
出去走走
will help you feel less anxious.
你就不焦虑了
I don't want to move.
不想动啊
I'm not in the mood.
没心情
If you come with me,
你要是跟我去的话
I'll give you a big gift
我给你准备一份
that you'll definitely love.
你绝对会喜欢的大礼
Bigger than that PhD application form?
比博士申请表还大
It holds a different meaning.
意义不一样
Fine.
好吧
The stars by the sea are so bright.
海边的星星真亮啊
If you like,
你喜欢的话
we can come here often.
我们常来
We can also see stars like these
这样的星星
from the rooftop where we have tutoring classes.
在辅导班的天台上也能看见啊
I think a certain someone
我看有的人
is just lazy.
其实就是懒
After building up the suspense for so long,
铺垫了这么久
you can
我的礼物
bring out the gift for me.
可以拿出来了
"All set."
搞定
I heard your call
你和余波打电话
with Yu Bo.
我可是听见了
When he said "all set,"
你说的搞定
did you mean you've secured a training ground?
是不是搞定场地了
I'm wrong?
猜错了
Then you can call Chairman Wang Genfa
那你现在可以给王根发董事长
now.
打电话了
Chairman Wang Genfa is very stingy.
王根发董事长很抠的
Then I'll make the call.
那我来打也行
You guessed right.
你猜对了
I've booked the best training facility in Hongjing
我订了宏景最好的训练场地
and a hotel where the team can stay together.
和集中管理的酒店
And I didn't book Hengjiu's place.
而且订的不是恒久
I paid for it myself.
我花的我的钱
No more words.
不多说了
Let's drink to it.
都在酒里
Cheers.
干杯
Are you cold?
冷吗
A bit.
有点
Come on.
来
A crab!
螃蟹
Where did it go?
去哪了
Where did you get it?
哪来的
They say when fireworks burn,
据说烟花燃烧的时候
they create a "wish frequency."
会产生愿望频率
If your heartbeat syncs with it at that moment,
如果这时候你心跳和它同步的话
your wish will definitely come true.
愿望就一定会实现
Looks like you've been reading
看来王大教练
quite a few psychology books, Coach Wang.
没少看心理学的书啊
Give it a try?
试试
Let's make a wish together
一起许愿
to win the championship.
拿下冠军
You know what?
你知道吗
These sparks are made of magnesium.
这些花火是由镁组成的
Magnesium reacts with carbon dioxide.
镁和二氧化碳会产生化学反应
So you can't put them out with a fire extinguisher.
用灭火器是灭不了的哦
You've switched to being a chemistry teacher, huh?
小林老师最近改当化学老师了
Wait.
等等
To put out the fire...
想要灭火
you just need to cover a large area
只需要大面积覆盖
to cut off the carbon dioxide.
隔绝二氧化碳
-The kids are urging us... -Let's go.
孩子们催 走
Let's go find them.
去找他们去
Good evening.
晚上好
-Ms. Lin.
小林老师 小林老师
Ms. Lin, Coach!
小林老师 教练
Play football...
踢球
-What's wrong? -I can walk by myself.
咋了这是
-Okay, okay. -Let me show you.
好好好
Ms. Lin is here. Ms. Lin is here.
老师来了
-Ms. Lin. -Coach.
小林老师 教练
-You called us here this late... -Attention.
大半夜把我们叫来聚在这里
Big drinker, tiny tolerance.
人菜瘾大
She's drunk.
高了
Please sit down, everyone.
大家请坐
Listen to your supervisor.
听老师的呀
Sit... Where should I sit?
坐 坐哪儿啊
Do you still remember
你们还记得
how you felt when you signed this football?
当时签这只球的心情是什么吗
Signed football.
签名足球
When we make it big,
等我们以后飞黄腾达
this'll be priceless.
这可是无价之宝
Now it really feels like a football team with star players.
有足球明星那味了啊
Yes.
有
Technique.
手法
My turn, my turn.
我来 我来 我来
Don't be so quick to forget.
别好了伤疤忘了疼
It's for Fu's sake.
为了老付
I'll just scribble something.
我就随便签了
Cool.
帅
Quit pretending, dude.
别装行吗 兄弟
Here, pen.
笔
So annoying.
真烦
Alright, boys.
好了宝宝们
It's about time.
时间差不多了
Hurry up and go to training.
快去训练吧
Whoever wasn't serious back then
当时谁不认真
knows it in their own heart.
自己心里清楚
Actually,
其实呢
there's something very important
我一直有一件很重要的事情
I still haven't done.
没有完成
Are you willing to sign it now, Mr. Coach?
现在愿意签了吧 大教练